A Guide to the Fauquier County (Va.) Records, circa 1810-1904, undated
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Fauquier County (Va.) Records, circa 1810-1904, undated
The Library of Virginia
1202626, 1209774-1203787
15 boxes--13 found at State Records Center--Archives Annex, Library of Virginia and 2 (1203778 and 1203784) found at Library of Virginia.
Fauquier County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records (1203774-1203787) came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Fauquier County under the accession number 37409. Records (1203780 and 1203781) have an additional accession number 37410.
Historical Information
Fauquier County was named for Francis Fauquier, lieutenant governor of Virginia from 1758-1768 The county was formed from Prince William County in 1759. The county seat is Warrenton.
Scope and Content
Fauquier County (Va.) Records, circa 1810-1904, undated, consist of the following series: Fiduciary Records, Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Road and Bridge Records, Court Records (subfield series include Chancery Records, Clerk's Records, Criminal Records, Jury Records and Court Finance Records), Tax and Fiscal Records, Business Records, Miscellaneous Records, Health and Medical Records, Justice of the Peace Records, Military and Pension Records, County Administrative Records (subfield series include Overseers of the Poor Records and Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records), Wills, Land Records and Marriage Records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Fauquier County Records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult "A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm" found on the Library of Virginia's web site.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Fauquier County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Public records--Virginia--Fauquier County.
Geographical Names:
Fauquier County (Va.)--History.
Genre and Form Terms:
Local government records--Virginia--Fauquier County.
Contents List
- Records, circa 1837-1880
  Fiduciary Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Orphan chancery records and Clerk's Records: Correspondence, etc.
- Records, 1810-1866
  Court Records: Clerk's Records and Criminal Records; Fiduciary Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Business Records; Miscellaneous Records: Estrays. Documents are flat-filed.
- Records, 1833-1850
  Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; Tax and Fiscal Records. Documents are flat-filed.
- Records, 1833-1849
  Fiduciary Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Court Records: Clerk's Records; Road and Bridge Records. Documents are flat-filed.
- Records, 1833-1853
  Tax and Fiscal Records; Fiduciary Records; Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; Health and Medical Records/Mental Health Records; Miscellaenous Records: Power of Attorney; Justice of the Peace Records. Documents are flat-filed.
- Records, 1833-1856, undated
  Tax and Fiscal Records; Military and Pension Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; Road and Bridge Records; Fiduciary Records; Court Records: Jury Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; County Administrative Records: Overseers of the Poor Records. Undated records are flat-filed.
- Records, 1833-1859
  Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records: Clerk's Records; Wills; Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Criminal Records and Jury Records; Justice of the Peace Records; Land Records; Marriage Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Court Records: Court Finance; Fiduciary Records. Documents are flat-filed.
- Records, 1859-1871
  Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records; Fiduciary Records; Justice of the Peace Records; Road and Bridge Records; Criminal Records. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1872-1878
  County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records; Fiduciary Records; Court Records: Criminal Records, Jury Records and Clerk's Records. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1879-1884
  Court Records: Criminal Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records: Jury Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths, Fiduciary Records. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1884-1888
  Court Records: Criminal Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records: Jury Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Fiduciary Records. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1889-1894
  Tax and Fiscal Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; Fiduciary Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Court Records: Jury Records. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1894-1898
  Health and Medical Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records: Jury Records; Fiduciary Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Court Records: Court Finance. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1899-1901
  County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Fiduciary Records; Court Records: Criminal Records, Court Finance and Jury Records; Bonds/Commissions/Oaths; Land Records; Wills. Records are unprocessed.
- Records, 1902-1904
  Land Records; Court Records: Criminal Records; Fiduciary Records; Miscellaneous Records: Power of Attorney; Court Records: Jury Records; Tax and Fiscal Records; Court Records: Court Finance; County Administrative Records: Board of Supervisors Records: Road and Bridge Records. Records are unprocessed.